clintonfoundation.org 2018-01-07

# Privacy Policy | Clinton Foundation

##### Effective: 04/29/16

The Bill, Hillary & Chelsea Clinton Foundation (the “Foundation”) Privacy Policy (“Policy”) was created to help you understand how the Foundation collects and uses information that is collected online through the Foundation’s websites: clintonfoundation.org, clintonglobalinitiative.org, clintonpresidentialcenter.org, noceilings.org, dineatfortytwo.com and clintonmuseumstore.com (each, a “Site”) or that you submit to the Foundation when making a donation. The Foundation is committed to protecting your privacy. By using this Site, you agree to be legally bound by this Policy and the [Terms of Use](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/terms-use), as they may be amended from time to time. If you do not agree to this Policy or cannot form a legally binding contract, you are not permitted to use this Site.

This Policy may also cover information collected and used by the Foundation via third party social media platforms, including Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and YouTube.

##### Information Collected

This Site collects two types of information from you: (1) General Information; and (2) Personal Information.  This information is used for the purposes for which it was collected (for example, responding to your requests, sending newsletters, administering surveys or processing donations), and the other limited purposes set forth below.

 **General Information**

The Foundation automatically collects some non-personal information (“General Information”) when you visit our Site via “cookies,” other tracking technology, registration forms, online surveys, etc., such as:

  * Your domain name and host for Internet access
  * The date and time of your entry
  * Your IP address, browser type, device, or operating system
  * The pages you visit and links that you use
  * The domain name from which you linked to our Site
  * Your city and state
  * Other general demographic information

We aggregate and analyze this usage information and use it for operational and administrative purposes, including to identify levels and area of interest in our website, and to improve and refine the Site. We may also share this aggregated, anonymous data with our business partners on an as-needed basis.

 **Personal Information**

The Foundation also collects information that may identify you (“Personal Information”) that you provide when making a donation to the Foundation (whether online, by mail or other physical means) or participating in any activity on a Site that requires your voluntarily submitted information, including completing any of our Site’s forms, for example, donation forms, registration forms, contact forms, online surveys, merchandise transactions, and position applications, such as:

  * Name
  * Mailing address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit card, payment card and bank information
  * Job, fellowship, internship, and volunteer position application information
  * Resumes and cover letters

##### Use of Information We Collect

We use the Personal Information for the purposes for which it was collected (for example, responding to your requests, sending newsletters, administering surveys or processing donations) and the limited purposes set forth below. The Foundation will not sell the Personal Information of donors for a third party’s fundraising or marketing purposes unless the donor explicitly grants permission to do so.  The Foundation will not exchange the Personal Information of donors for a third party’s fundraising or marketing purposes if a donor opts out of allowing the Foundation to do so.  To opt out of exchanges of Personal Information for third party fundraising or marketing purposes, please send us an email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#dabebfacbfb6b5aab7bfb4ae9ab9b6b3b4aeb5b4bcb5afb4bebbaeb3b5b4f4b5a8bd).  Further, we do not share, sell, transfer, exchange or disclose your Personal Information with third parties except in the following limited circumstances:

  * To carry out the Foundation’s mission. Specifically, we may share your e-mail or mailing address with our subsidiaries and affiliated entities, and certain third parties with whom we work, for use for a specific, limited purpose related to the Foundation’s mission and goals, which may include responding to your requests, processing donations or merchandise orders, sending newsletters, surveys, notices or content, and administering, enhancing and troubleshooting the Site and the Foundation’s other online offerings
  * With your permission to disclose the information
  * To change website hosts or when our host transfers business assets (as further described below)
  * To share it with third party vendors, agents or contractors who perform services for us on a “need to know” basis
  * As required by law or court order (see “Legal Disclaimer” below) or to comply with the Foundation’s donor disclosure obligations (see “Donor Disclosure” below)

##### Control of Your Personal Information

If you prefer to not share your Personal Information as described above, please email us at any time at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#10747566757c7f607d757e6450737c797e647f7e767f657e747164797f7e3e7f6277).

##### Donor Disclosure

Please note that the Foundation is obligated to disclose all donors, which it does by listing donors by range of donation amount on our website. View the contributors list [here](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/contributors).

##### Corrections/Updates

This Site gives users the opportunity to change Personal Information previously provided to us through this Site. To do so, please send us an email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d1b5b4a7b4bdbea1bcb4bfa591b2bdb8bfa5bebfb7bea4bfb5b0a5b8bebfffbea3b6). If you have registered to receive emails from the Foundation and later change your mind, you may contact us to have your name removed from our distribution lists by sending us an email through our [Contact Page](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/about/contact-us), or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of every email sent from the Foundation.

##### Transfer of Business Assets

At any time, this Site’s host may be acquired, merge with another business, or acquire or buy other businesses or assets. In such transactions, both General and Personal Information will likely be among the transferred assets.

##### Cookies, Tracking Tags, and Other Technology

The Site may use cookies and other tracking mechanisms across our Site and social media platforms. Cookies allow the Foundation to measure activity on the Site and to improve your user experience by, for example, remembering your passwords and viewing preferences and allowing you to visit any member-only parts of the Site without re-registering.  Cookies cannot retrieve any other data from a hard drive or obtain an email address.  Although a user has the ability to modify most browsers to either accept all cookies, notify the user when a cookie is sent, or reject all cookies, it may not be possible to use certain services on this Site if cookies are not accepted.

The Foundation may use electronic images known as web beacons to monitor activity on our website, as well as across social media platforms and other websites. These web beacons allow the Foundation to provide personalized services and advertising content. With both cookies and web beacon technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable.

##### Our Commitment to Data Security

Personal Information is stored on our server and the servers of our third party vendors who perform services for us and is not publicly accessible.  Further, Personally Information is only accessed by Foundation staff on a "need to know" basis.  To prevent unauthorized access and maintain data accuracy, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.  Additionally, sensitive data such as credit card numbers are encrypted using SSL and other industry standard measures, to provide an additional level of security.

##### Links

This Site contains links to other sites.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of or the contents on any other websites.  We encourage you to review the privacy policy and any other online policies of other websites that you link to, visit, and/or use.

##### Children

The Site does not seek to collect any information from children under 13.  If a child provides us with information, the parent or guardian may notify us, and the information will be deleted from our records.

##### Security

While there is no such thing as “perfect” security on the Internet, we take reasonable steps to protect the safety of your personal information. This Site has security measures in place to protect loss, misuse, and/or alteration of such information under our control. However, we do not guarantee the security of your General or Personal Information. In addition, we do not assume any liability for third party use of your General or Personal Information, whether obtained legally or illegally from or through this Site.

##### Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Foundation may update this Policy at any time.  Any changes to the Policy will be reflected on this “Privacy Policy” page, and by using this Site subsequent to any changes, you agree to those changes.  We may also notify you about significant changes in the way we treat Personal Information through such means as sending a notice to the email address that you have provided us or placing a prominent notice on our Site.

##### Legal Disclaimer

We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the Foundation. Although we use security that we believe to be appropriate to protect your Personal Information, we do not guarantee that our security precautions will protect against, and we expressly disclaim any liability for, any loss, misuse, or alteration of your Personal Information.

##### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#711d1416101d31121d181f051e1f171e041f151005181e1f5f1e0316) or send us a message through our Contact Page. You may also contact us via mail at: The Bill, Hillary & Chelsea Clinton Foundation,1200 President Clinton Avenue, Little Rock, Arkansas 72201

THE USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO THE TERMS OF USE, INCLUDING THIS PRIVACY POLICY.
